piac.com.pk 2019-11-07

# Privacy Policy - Pakistan International Airlines - PIA

###### Privacy

At PIA we are committed to respecting your privacy. This policy describes how we collect, use and disclose personal information concerning our guests and other individuals. This policy may be modified from time to time by posting updated versions on the PIA website and you may also be notified of changes upon logging in to the website.

#### What is personal information?

Personal information is information about an identifiable individual. Your personal information includes:

  * Identification number (ID)
  * Email address
  * User ID (UID)
  * Messages on social media
  * Genetic, physiological, or physical information
  * Medical information
  * Location
  * Bank details
  * IP address
  * Cookies
  * You’re Name
  * Telephone number

Email address, and any other information that identifies who you are or would allow someone to contact you. Personal information only becomes known to PIA when you provide it to us, or when a third party, such as a travel agent, family member or other party books a ticket on your behalf and provides personal information to PIA with your consent.

#### Consent

It is our policy to collect, use and discloses personal information about you with your knowledge and consent, unless otherwise required or allowed by law. Prior to collecting personal information, it is our policy to identify the purposes for doing so and to limit the collection, use and disclosure of personal information to those purposes.  
Generally, we will collect personal information from you, and use it and disclose it with express consent received from you or from someone on your behalf. There will be occasions where we will rely on opt-out consent with respect to contacting you with offers that we feel will be of interest to you. We will use opt out consent only in circumstances where the personal information in question is not sensitive, where the purposes and circumstances are limited and well-defined and brought to your attention at the time personal information is collected, or where you are given an opportunity to opt-out or withdraw your consent then or at any time by contacting us.  
If we identify a new purpose for using or disclosing your personal information, unless otherwise required by law, we will contact you to obtain your consent for the new use or disclosure and we may use your contact information, including your email address, to do so.

#### Collection and use of personal information

If you would like to fly with us, book a accommodation or car, join a mailing list, apply for a job, participate in a program or enter a contest that may be offered by PIA from time to time, you will be asked for personal information as described in this policy and as stated to you at the time of collection. Personal information may be collected by us through our call centre, or by interaction with our Website, or from you in person, or about you by us from a travel agent or other party obtaining travel services for you on your behalf.

It is our policy to collect personal information about you directly from you where possible or reasonable to do so. However, there are circumstances where personal information about you will be collected from a third party obtaining travel services for you on your behalf with your consent.

Personal information provided by you or on your behalf to book flights or other travel services will generally not be provided to anyone, including a spouse, family member, friend or coworker, without your consent, or as required by law, or as otherwise provided in this privacy policy. To protect your privacy rights and personal information, and for security and legal purposes, we therefore generally cannot disclose your personal information to any individual contacting us and claiming either to be a spouse, family member, friend, co-worker or otherwise entitled to your personal information, or claiming to have your consent for us to do so, unless and until we have verified with you that you do in fact consent to our disclosure of your personal information to such specified individual. The exceptions to this are:

*We will disclose your personal information on a reasonable basis to an individual who has booked your current flight or other travel service where that individual has adequately identified themselves. We will consider that, since they previously had your consent, express or implied, to deal with us, your consent continues. Please Agent or Account Manager in Terms Of Use.

*Where an individual contacts us and provides us with your full name and booking confirmation number giving us reasonable grounds to conclude they are contacting us with your consent, express or implied, we will disclose flight information to that individual for the purposes of permitting that individual to meet your flight or be aware of delays, and other similar information. Flight information is limited to flight number, flight timing information, confirmation that you have or have not boarded a flight, and the departure and arrival locations of your journey with us. Flight information is provided as a service and convenience to you to permit meeting your flight and being aware of any delays or flights that are early. We will not provide other personal information such as home address or contact information to other individuals in these circumstances without your express consent. If you do not wish individuals to be able to obtain flight information from us, you should not share your PNR number with them. Otherwise, we will conclude that, where an individual has your full name and booking confirmation number you have given your consent to their contacting us for your flight information. Booking confirmation number refers to the confirmation number assigned by PIA to you for a specific flight.

#### Booking a Flight

When you book a flight with us, or when someone books a flight with us on your behalf, we will ask for your gender, name, address, email address, phone number, and credit card information. We collect this information in order to process your request for travel services or to process refunds. We need your gender to determine the weight and balance of our aircraft and to assist us in identifying you for legal and security purposes. We may also use your personal information to contact you about your flight booking or about anything that may affect your flight booking or your flight.  
PIA may also use your personal information to contact you about your travel patterns and your experiences when flying with us.  
Adequate personal identification documents, including photographic likenesses, will generally be required in order to permit you to board an aircraft or access other services. This information is collected for security, legal and identification purposes and is generally returned to you immediately and not retained.

#### Requirements of Government Authorities

Because of the nature of the airline industry, and concerns with respect to safety and security, there may be situations in which PIA is required by legal authorities to collect, use or disclose personal information about you, particularly when you are traveling with us, without your knowledge or consent. Information that we are required to collect by any Canadian government authorities, depending on your boarding location and destination, may include, as required by such authorities, your full name, date of birth, citizenship, gender, passport number and country of issuance, drivers license and province of issuance or other photo identification, the means by which you paid for your flight, details as to how it was booked, and any other personal information collected by us as set out in this policy or as required by such government authority.

Special Needs and Unaccompanied Minors

Subject to certain restrictions and the PIA Local Domestic Tariff, services are offered to persons with special needs and for unaccompanied minors.

In order to properly serve persons with special needs, and to assure the health and safety of all concerned, PIA may require additional personal information, including relevant medical information and information on particular requirements, such as whether a wheelchair, oxygen supply or other special equipment are required, as well as additional contact information in the event of an emergency.

In order to serve unaccompanied minors, PIA will require personal information concerning adult(s) dropping off the child at the commencement of their travel with PIA as well as the adult(s) meeting the child at the conclusion of their travel with Harbour Air, as well as additional contact information in the event of an emergency. We do not allow unaccompanied minors to proceed to flights with other carriers without first being met by a designated adult or adults. For security purposes, we may ask the designated adult or adults for sufficient personal information, including personal identification with photographic likenesses, returning such information to the designated adult or adults once identity has been verified.

#### Agents

When you book with us through an Agent, your Agent will provide us with the same personal information that we would otherwise collect from you directly in order to book a flight or other travel services. Unless and until we are advised otherwise, we will consider an Agent to have your authority to provide us with your personal information to be used and disclosed by us pursuant to this privacy policy. Collection, use and disclosure of your personal information by your Agent will be subject to your dealings with the Agent and their privacy policies and practices.

Agent access to online information from PIA is governed both by PIA policies and by restrictions and levels of permission set up by the Agent. Personnel in each Agents office may be able to gain access to personal information concerning all clients and customers of the Agents. Access to your personal information may not be limited to the individual Agent you have dealt with as Agents may share information. Any inquiries about another Agenct accessing your personal information should be directed to the original Agenct with whom you booked your flight. See Agent in Terms Of Use.

#### Account Manager Bookings

If a third party, including a family member or friend, or your employer or another party other than a travel agent, has made or will be making a booking on your behalf, that party will provide us with the same personal information that we would otherwise collect from you directly in order to book a flight or other travel services. Unless and until we are advised otherwise, we will consider such third party to have your authority to provide us with your personal information to be used and disclosed pursuant to this privacy policy. Collection, use and disclosure of your personal information by a third party will be subject to your dealings with them and any applicable privacy policy and practices they may have.

Certain employers and other parties may be granted access to online information from PIA with respect to your booking where your employer or other party has made that booking on your behalf. Such access is governed by our TERMS OF USE. Such other party, including any others to whom it grants permission, will be able to gain access to personal information concerning all individuals for whom they have made bookings. See Account Manager in Terms Of Use.

#### PIA Member and Mailing Lists

Our Live Online Booking feature allows you to provide us with your personal information for your convenience in using our website, should you choose to enroll. We strive to continuously improve the function of the fields available, but unless we advise you otherwise, any improvement in or addition to the fields will be subject to the same policies as set out in this policy.

For certain opt-in services, PIA may, with your consent, collect profile information about you, as well as demographic information. This information will be used to communicate specific information to you based on the profile and demographic information you provide.

If you would like to do any one or more of the following:

  1. join our frequent flyer mailing list and be informed of discounts and other promotional offers;
  2. be informed of new routes and services; or
  3. participate in research surveys from time to time,

you must first set up a frequent flyer Online Booking profile and check the applicable option or options, following which we will use your profile to communicate with you via email as you have requested. You may withdraw your consent to any of the foregoing options at any time.

#### Promotional Contests

PIA may offer various promotions from time to time. When you enter a promotional contest, we ask for your name, date of birth, address (email and/or residential) and phone number so that we may communicate with you in the event you are a winner and so that we may verify that you are of sufficient age to participate or that you meet other eligibility requirements stated in any specific contest rules. Other information related to the promotion or contest may be requested if required by law.

#### Employment Opportunities

PIA offers employment opportunities over its website. If you would like to apply for a job at PIA, you will be asked to provide your name, telephone number, address, email address, and other information concerning your application such as employment history, references and education. This information is used to contact you and to review your application, including to contact any references on your behalf or any other third parties that you may consent to our contacting and discussing your work history and related matters.

#### Cookies

A cookie is a small amount of data, often including an anonymous unique identifier, that is sent to your browser from a website’s computer and stored on your computer’s hard drive. We use “cookies” to collect and compile general statistical data – cookies do not give us access to any of your personal information. Cookies track the movements of visitors to our website and allow us to collect anonymous information about visitor website usage patterns to better understand and meet their requirements with improved website design. If you have registered with us, cookies also allow our website to recognize your computer the next time you visit and sign in and automatically fill in fields as mentioned above in PIA Member and Mailing Lists.

#### Disclosure

PIA discloses your personal information with your consent to third parties as required to process your request for travel services, including flights, hotel and car bookings, and to provide services to you, or as required by applicable law, or as otherwise set out in this policy.

PIA is continuously seeking ways in which to better serve you. PIA may therefore also disclose personal information concerning you to other organizations who may have affiliated programs to PIA or other offers of interest to you to allow them to contact you, but PIA will do so only with your consent, which you may withdraw at any time.

Partners and Related Service Suppliers

PIA may provide you with the opportunity to access products and services from third parties. Those third parties may collect, use and disclose personal information from you or about you in order to provide their products or services to you. The collection, use and disclosure of personal information by those third parties will be governed by their privacy policies and any consent you provide and, unless we advise you otherwise, PIA has no access to or control over your personal information collected from you by those third parties.

#### Requirements of Government Authorities

As mentioned above, we are required to collect personal information by government authorities in Pakistan, and that information may be disclosed to those authorities without your knowledge or consent as required by law. It is the policy of PIA to only collect and disclose what is required by law, and nothing further.  
Security  
PIA has in place security measures and procedures to ensure that your personal information is protected from misuse and from unauthorized access.  
However, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. We cannot ensure the security of the information you transmit to us over the Internet.

RETENTION OF INFORMATION

#### Retention periods

Personal information collected by PIA is retained for as long as it is reasonably required for the purposes for which it was collected, or as required by law, following which it is securely destroyed or made anonymous. If you withdraw your consent to our retaining your personal information, we will advise you as to the consequences, if any, of your doing so.

#### Accessing your personal information

Feel free to contact us if you have any questions or concerns about this policy or the accuracy and completeness of any information in your file, if you wish to update any of your information, if you would like to see a copy of the information we have on file about you, or an account of the use that has been made of your information. To do so, simply contact PIA at:

**Toll Free: 111 786 111**

You may also use the above information to withdraw any consent you have provided, or to register a concern or complaint with us. In all cases, we may require that requests for information or withdrawal of consent be received by us by email or otherwise in written form. We will also require that you provide sufficient information to allow us to locate your information to deal with your request.

#### Responding to you

All requests for access to information and complaints must be provided in writing and our response will be subject verifying your identity before replying. At this time we do not accept requests or complaints via email. It is our policy to respond to all inquiries, requests for access to personal information and concerns or complaints within 30 days of our receiving them unless otherwise allowed or required by law. If we cannot fully respond within 30 days, we will still advise you of that within 30 days.

However, we cannot give you access to personal information that we do not have, or that would disclose personal information concerning another individual without their consent, or that we otherwise cannot disclose under applicable law. There are legal restrictions in certain cases where we are prohibited from providing you with certain information. We reserve the right, in limited circumstances, to refuse to provide access to information where not legally required to do so, in which case we will advise you of the reasons for doing so, of the name of a person who can answer any questions you may have, and other details of your legal rights.

* * *
